<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on SivaLabs</title>
    <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on SivaLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 02:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sivalabs.github.io/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP AngularJS! Oh Sorry, RIP $scope, ng-controller, DDO, jqLite and whatever you like in AngularJS</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/10/rip-angularjs-oh-sorry-rip-scope-ng-controller-ddo-jqlite-and-whatever-you-like-in-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 02:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/10/rip-angularjs-oh-sorry-rip-scope-ng-controller-ddo-jqlite-and-whatever-you-like-in-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>I am &amp;nbsp;Software Developer, specifically Java Developer, spending most of the time writing back-end part of the applications. I can write basic HTML/JavaScript/CSS stuff to get the things done when needed. I didn&amp;#8217;t have much passion on HTML/JavaScript and neither I am good at web development. I just has good enough knowledge to get the front-end work done for my requirements. Whenever I find sometime I tried to experiment with some cool back-end technologies like SpringBoot or JavaEE7, I never spend my weekends learning any front-end technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS: Different ways of using Array Filters</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/09/angularjs-different-ways-of-using-array-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 01:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/09/angularjs-different-ways-of-using-array-filters/</guid>
      <description>AngularJS provides filter feature which can be used to format input value or to filter an Array with the given matching input criteria. For example you can use &amp;#8216;date&amp;#8217; filter to format a Date value into human readable Date representation like MM-DD-YYYY as {{dob | date}}.
On the other hand there are Array filtering feature which is very useful while filtering data from an Array of JavaScript objects. The Array filtering is very commonly used with a Table along with ng-repeat directive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS: Introducing modules, controllers, services</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/09/angularjs-introducing-modules-controllers-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 07:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/09/angularjs-introducing-modules-controllers-services/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post AngularJS Tutorial: Getting Started with AngularJS we have seen how to setup an application using SpringBoot + AngularJS + WebJars. But it&amp;#8217;s a kind of quick start tutorial where I haven&amp;#8217;t explained much about AngularJS modules, controllers and services. Also it is a single screen (only one route) application.
In this part-2 tutorial, we will take a look at what are Angular modules, controllers and services and how to configure and use them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS Tutorial: Getting Started with AngularJS</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/09/angularjs-tutorial-getting-started-with-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 08:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/09/angularjs-tutorial-getting-started-with-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>AngularJS is a popular JavaScript framework for building Single Page Applications (SPAs).
AngularJS provides the following features which makes developing web apps easy:
 Two way data binding
 Dependency Injection
 Custom HTML Directives
 Easy integration with REST webservices using $http, $resource, Restangular etc
 Support for Testing
  and many more&amp;#8230;
Though there are lot more features than the above mentioned list, these are the very commonly used features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to POST and GET JSON between EXTJS and SpringMVC3</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2011/06/how-to-post-and-get-json-between-extjs-and-springmvc3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 02:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2011/06/how-to-post-and-get-json-between-extjs-and-springmvc3/</guid>
      <description>After one month of evaluation of the frameworks and tools, i choose ExtJS for UI and Spring/SpringMVC for business layer for my pet project.
Again by using ExtJS we can send data to server by form submits or as request parameters or in json format through Ajax requests. ExtJS uses JSON format in many situations to hold data. So I thought using JSON as data exchange format between EXTJS and Spring will be consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>