<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spring on SivaLabs</title>
    <link>https://sivalabs.in/tags/spring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spring on SivaLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 12:30:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sivalabs.in/tags/spring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cloud Tutorials – Auto Refresh Config Changes using Spring Cloud Bus</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2017/08/spring-cloud-tutorials-auto-refresh-config-changes-using-spring-cloud-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2017/08/spring-cloud-tutorials-auto-refresh-config-changes-using-spring-cloud-bus/</guid>
      <description>Problem In the previous article Introduction to Spring Cloud Config Server we have seen how to use Spring Cloud Config Server.
But, the problem is to reload the config changes in Config Client applications we need to trigger /refresh endpoint manually. This is not practical and viable if you have large number of applications.
Solution Spring Cloud Bus module can be used to link multiple applications with a message broker and we can broadcast configuration changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cloud Tutorials – Introduction to Spring Cloud Config Server</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2017/08/spring-cloud-tutorials-introduction-to-spring-cloud-config-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 03:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2017/08/spring-cloud-tutorials-introduction-to-spring-cloud-config-server/</guid>
      <description>Problem SpringBoot provides lot of flexibility in externalizing configuration properties via properties or YAML files. We can also configure properties for each environment (dev, qa, prod etc) separately using profile specific configuration files such as application.properties, application-dev.properties, application-prod.properties etc. But once the application is started we can not update the properties at runtime. If we change the properties we need to restart the application to use the updated configuration properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Review of Sanjay Patel’s Spring Course</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2016/06/my-review-of-sanjay-patels-spring-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 01:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2016/06/my-review-of-sanjay-patels-spring-course/</guid>
      <description>Spring is the most popular Java framework for building web and enterprise applications. There are plenty of official documentation, books, and Training Courses available for Spring framework on web.
I got an opportunity to review Sanjay Patel&amp;#8216;s Spring Course Material which is divided into 3 modules.
http://www.naturalprogrammer.com/spring-tutorial/
The total course is divided into 3 modules covering various aspects of web application development using Spring/SpringBoot framework.
 Module I : Spring Framework 4 And Dependency Injection For Beginners Module II : Spring Framework for the Real World Module III : Spring Framework REST API Development  Module I: Spring Framework 4 and Dependency Injection For Beginners</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrying Method Execution using Spring AOP</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2016/01/retrying-method-execution-using-spring-aop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 15:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2016/01/retrying-method-execution-using-spring-aop/</guid>
      <description>One of my blog follower sends an email asking me to show an example of &amp;#8220;RealWorld Usage of Spring AOP&amp;#8221;. He mentioned that in most of the examples the usage of Spring AOP is demonstrated for logging method entry/exit or Transaction management or Security checks. He wanted to know how Spring AOP is being used in &amp;#8220;Real Project for Real Problems&amp;#8221;.
So I would like to show how I have used Spring AOP for one of my project to handle a real problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting The Technology Stack for JCart</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2015/11/selecting-the-technology-stack-for-jcart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 05:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2015/11/selecting-the-technology-stack-for-jcart/</guid>
      <description>Selecting the right technology stack is very crucial and plays an important role in project success. Many of the architects (unknowingly??!!) try to make complex designs by trying to use all kinds of latest and greatest stuff. On the other hand some architects try to be in their comfort zone by limiting their technology stack to the technologies with which they are comfortable. Both approaches are dangerous. One should understand the business needs and pick the technologies that are necessary for project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a simple e-commerce application from scratch to production using SpringBoot</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2015/11/developing-a-simple-e-commerce-application-from-scratch-to-production-using-springboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 14:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2015/11/developing-a-simple-e-commerce-application-from-scratch-to-production-using-springboot/</guid>
      <description>We can find plenty of information on any technical topic, be it Java, .NET, Python or any frameworks like Spring, Hibernate, CDI, JSF etc. You can find hundreds of well written blogs on many of these topics. For example, you can find lot of tutorials on how to use SpringBoot or how to use various mappings in JPA/Hibernate or how to do form validations in JSF etc. Also, there are plenty of books published by well established publishers on most of the technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developers Perspective on Spring vs JavaEE</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2015/06/a-developers-perspective-on-spring-vs-javaee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2015/06/a-developers-perspective-on-spring-vs-javaee/</guid>
      <description>In Java community Spring vs JavaEE is a never ending debate. In such debates people form two groups consisting of evangelists, architects and hard core fans of one platform and debate endlessly. Those who participate in the debates may be architects who are responsible for platform selection. But what would developers think about this Spring vs JavaEE debate?
I am a Java developer who uses both Spring and JavaEE and I am not part of Spring or JavaEE fan club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bunch of Maven Archetypes for Spring based Projects</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2012/10/a-bunch-of-maven-archetypes-for-spring-based-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2012/10/a-bunch-of-maven-archetypes-for-spring-based-projects/</guid>
      <description>Maven is a good project management tool which&amp;nbsp;greatly&amp;nbsp;reduces the amount of time we spend on creating java projects with proper structure.&amp;nbsp;With so many&amp;nbsp;predefined&amp;nbsp;maven archetypes it is even easier to create projects by simply selecting the archetype based on the technologies we need and type(jar/war/ear) of project we want to create.
However sometimes those predefined archetypes structure may not suite well for our needs or we may need some more additions to the pre-configured dependencies/frameworks etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyBatis Tutorial : Part4 – Spring Integration</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.in/2012/10/mybatis-tutorial-part4-spring-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.in/2012/10/mybatis-tutorial-part4-spring-integration/</guid>
      <description>MyBatis Tutorial: Part1 &amp;#8211; CRUD Operations
MyBatis Tutorial: Part-2: CRUD operations Using Annotations
MyBatis Tutorial: Part 3 &amp;#8211; Mapping Relationships
MyBatis Tutorial : Part4 &amp;#8211; Spring Integration
MyBatis-Spring is a sub-project of MyBatis and provides Spring integration support which drastically simplifies the MyBatis usage. For those who are familiar with Spring&amp;#8217;s way of Dependency Injection process, using MyBatis-Spring is a very simple.
First let us see the process of using MyBatis without Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>