<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interviews on SivaLabs</title>
    <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/tags/interviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interviews on SivaLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 06:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://sivalabs.github.io/tags/interviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Are frameworks making developers dumb?</title>
      <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2011/frameworks-making-developers-dumb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 06:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2011/frameworks-making-developers-dumb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I got to take interviews to hire senior java developers with around 5 years of experience. But after the interview process is over I felt like the frameworks makes developers life easier but at the same time  making them dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone puts almost all the new frameworks on their resume claiming they have &amp;ldquo;Strong, working experience on Spring, Hibernate, Web Services etc&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how the interviews went on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; You have used Spring in your latest project. What are the advantages of using Spring?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; We can configure beans in XML and it will take care of instantiating and give it to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Me: **If Spring is for only creating objects why is it required at all, I can directly instantiate the dependencies using &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo;. Why should I configure the class names in XML and get the object from Spring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; If tomorrow we want to create another implementation of our interface we can create new implementation and update the XML configuration to use new impl. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to change Java class and compile them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; But you are writing a new Java class, so obviously you need to compile the project.&lt;br /&gt;
Regarding XML change, 99% of the times your XML will be packaged in war or ear file.&lt;br /&gt;
So you will run ANT script and create the war with the all the new changes.&lt;br /&gt;
Then your point of &amp;ldquo;if it is XML i don&amp;rsquo;t need to compile&amp;rdquo; is not a valid point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; Hmmm, But the Dependency Injection design pattern suggests to follow this way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; OK. I am done with the interview. Our HR will get back to you. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interview with another guy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Can you explain about your latest project and what technologies have you used?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; It is some XYZ System and we are using Spring, Hibernate, REST WebServices.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Ok. Can you explain something about RESTful architecture?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; We can develop RESTful application by using @RequestMapping(value=&amp;ldquo;/url&amp;rdquo;, method=&amp;ldquo;POST&amp;rdquo;). And also we can use PUT, DELETE methods.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; That OK, but what is the concept of RESTful architecture?&lt;br /&gt;
**Interviewee: **That&amp;rsquo;s what I am explaining. If you use @RequestMapping(value=&amp;ldquo;/url&amp;rdquo;, method=&amp;ldquo;POST&amp;rdquo;) you can develop RESTful application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Ok, How good are you in Hibernate?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; I am using Hibernate for the last 2 years. I am very good in using Hibernate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; What are the advantages of using Hibernate over JDBC?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; By using we don&amp;rsquo;t need to write anything to interact with database, Hibernate will take care of.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; How Hibernate comes to know about your project requirement?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; If we use Hibernate it will take care saving, updating and fetching data from database.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Uffffffuuuuu&amp;hellip; OK.. In your free time do you read any technology related blogs?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Interviewee:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, why not. That how I learn Hibernate in-depth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me :&lt;/strong&gt; Very Good, nice talking to you. Our HR will get back to you. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interview process went on like this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe frameworks will increase developer productivity. But the developers should try to understand how the framework is doing the stuff. You need not learn all the internal working mechanisms of frameworks. If you are really good at Servlets and JSP then it is very easy to understand any Java Web framework like Struts, SpringMVC etc.If you aren&amp;rsquo;t good at the basics then obviously for every other question  reply would be.. &amp;ldquo;framework&amp;rsquo;s annotation/xml will execute this&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly recommend the people who want to start their career as a Java developer to work on Core Java, Servlets, JSP for sometime.Then only one can understand the frameworks in proper way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMS Interview Questions</title>
      <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/jms-interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 06:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/jms-interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is JMS?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many types of JMS domains are there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain about P2P / Point-To-Point Messaging?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain about Publish/Subscribe Messaging?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What kind of information will contain in a JMS message?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you get the messages from a Queue/Topic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many types of Messages are there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between ByteMessages and StreamMessage?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you get Acknowledgment from the receiver?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What will happen if the Receivers are down when the Message arrives to the Queue/Topic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EJB Interview Questions</title>
      <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/ejb-interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 06:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/ejb-interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is EJB?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the services provided by the EJB technology?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many types of EJB’s are there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between Stateful and Stateless EJBs?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is a MessageDrivenBean?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you get the reference of an EJB from the EJB Container?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a Remote Interface and a Local Interface?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are all the ways to handle transactions?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When do you go for declarative transaction management and Programmatic Transaction Management?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain about the life cycle of a Stateless and Stateful SessionBean?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Struts1.x Interview Questions</title>
      <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/struts1x-interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/struts1x-interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is Struts Framework?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain about the life cycle of a request in Struts?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is ActionServlet?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are Action classes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is Action classes are thread-Safe?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the built in Action classes in Struts?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many types of ActionForms are there in Struts?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you handle duplicate form submissions?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the default scope of a FormBean in struts-config.xml?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you develop i18n application in Struts?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servlets and JSP Interview Questions</title>
      <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/servlets-and-jsp-interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 05:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/servlets-and-jsp-interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is a Servlet?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain about Servlet life cycle?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you mean by Idempotent request?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a GET and POST request?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between request.forward() and response.sendRedirect() methods?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Interview Questions</title>
      <link>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/java-interview-questions_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sivalabs.github.io/post/2009/java-interview-questions_05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are JDK, JRE and JVM ?&lt;br /&gt;
A. **JDK: **Java Developer Kit contains tools needed to develop the Java programs, and JRE to run the programs. The tools include compiler (javac.exe), Java application launcher (java.exe), Appletviewer, etc…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compiler converts java code into byte code. Java application launcher opens a JRE, loads the class, and invokes its main method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need JDK, if at all you want to write your own programs, and to compile them. For running java programs, JRE is sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**JRE: **Java Runtime Environment contains JVM, class libraries, and other supporting files. Actually JVM runs the program, and it uses the class libraries, and other supporting files provided in JRE. If you want to run any java program, you need to have JRE installed in the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**JVM: **Java Virtual Machine interprets the bytecode into the machine code depending upon the underlying operating system and hardware combination. It is responsible for all the things like garbage collection, array bounds checking, etc… JVM is platform dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JVM is called &amp;ldquo;virtual&amp;rdquo; because it provides a machine interface that does not depend on the underlying operating system and machine hardware architecture. This independence from hardware and operating system is a cornerstone of the write-once run-anywhere value of Java programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the OOPS Concepts?&lt;br /&gt;
A. The four basic pillars of OOPS are Abstraction, Encapsulation, Polymorphism and Inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain about Abstraction, Encapsulation, Polymorphism, and Inheritance?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.What is a Class and Object?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.What is an Interface?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.What is an Abstract Class?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7.When do you go for an Abstract Class and an Interface?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8.How do you achieve Polymorphism in Java?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9.What are the access modifiers in Java?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10.What is the significance of static, final, finally, finalize keywords?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11.Explain why the main method has public, static and void modifiers in Java?&lt;br /&gt;
A.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>