<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on SivaLabs</title>
    <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on SivaLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 04:59:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sivalabs.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Review of Vlad Mihalcea’s High-Performance Java Persistence book</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2017/11/my-review-of-vlad-mihalceas-high-performance-java-persistence-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 04:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2017/11/my-review-of-vlad-mihalceas-high-performance-java-persistence-book/</guid>
      <description>In Java world, JPA/Hibernate is the most popular and widely used framework. When it comes to overall performance of a software system database persistence layer plays the crucial role. The tricky part with JPA/Hibernate is it is very easy to get started but very very hard to master. This is where Vlad Mihalcea&amp;#8216;s High-Performance Java Persistence book helps you a lot.

The High-Performance Java Persistence book is not just another Hibernate book saying you put this annotation here and call that method there and you are done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Books</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/mybooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 02:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/mybooks/</guid>
      <description> Beginning Spring Boot 2 SpringBoot : Learn By Example PrimeFaces Beginners Guide Java Persistence with MyBatis3 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Book SpringBoot : Learn By Example Published Today</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2016/07/my-new-book-springboot-learn-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 06:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2016/07/my-new-book-springboot-learn-by-example/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce that my new book SpringBoot : Learn By Example got published today on Leanpub.
SpringBoot : Learn By Example  &amp;nbsp;
  What is SpringBoot?
Spring is one of the most popular Java frameworks out there to build web and enterprise application.
Spring supports variety of configuration approaches (XML, Annotations, JavaConfig etc) and properly configuring Spring applications become a bit tedious and repetitive process. To avoid these problems Spring team introduced SpringBoot to address the complexity of configuring Spring application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>