<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>E Commerce on SivaLabs</title>
    <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/tags/e-commerce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in E Commerce on SivaLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 04:34:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sivalabs.github.io/tags/e-commerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the Development Environment for JCart</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/setting-up-the-development-environment-for-jcart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 04:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/setting-up-the-development-environment-for-jcart/</guid>
      <description>For our JCart application development we will be using the following Softwares/Tools.
  JDK 8 SpringSource Tool Suite (STS)  MySQL Git  Maven  Jenkins  SonarQube  Apache/Nginx WebServer  I am not going to explain how to install JDK or MySQL because there are plenty of articles you can find on internet.
If you are using Ubuntu based Linux Operating System then you can refer my article My Development Environment Setup on Linux to setup Java development tool chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCart Release Planning</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/jcart-release-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 04:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/jcart-release-planning/</guid>
      <description>In our previous article JCart Requirements Analysis we have listed out all the requirements that we need to implement for JCart application. Now we need to come up with an implementation and release plan. As we are following iteration model, we will plan for N iterations where in each iteration we will implement some usecases.
After listing out all the implementation tasks and based on the task dependencies, we came up with the following Iteration plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting The Technology Stack for JCart</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/selecting-the-technology-stack-for-jcart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 05:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/selecting-the-technology-stack-for-jcart/</guid>
      <description>Selecting the right technology stack is very crucial and plays an important role in project success. Many of the architects (unknowingly??!!) try to make complex designs by trying to use all kinds of latest and greatest stuff. On the other hand some architects try to be in their comfort zone by limiting their technology stack to the technologies with which they are comfortable. Both approaches are dangerous. One should understand the business needs and pick the technologies that are necessary for project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCart Requirements Analysis</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/jcart-requirements-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 11:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/jcart-requirements-analysis/</guid>
      <description>For building our JCart e-commerce application we will develop two web applications, one for ShoppingCart and another one for Administration. Let us explore the requirements of both ShoppingCart and Administration websites in detail.
ShoppingCart Site Requirements Home Page: This page shows list of categories and few products in each category. From this screen customers can click on any Category name to see all the products in that particular category or can add a product to cart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the application JCart</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/introducing-the-application-jcart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 02:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/introducing-the-application-jcart/</guid>
      <description>As I promised in my article Developing a simple e-commerce application from scratch to production using SpringBoot , I am starting first post by introducing the application JCart that we are going to build.
One of my friend makes quilling toys and she sell them by advertising on Facebook or through word of mouth. Now she is getting more and more customers and she wants to expand her business by going online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a simple e-commerce application from scratch to production using SpringBoot</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/developing-a-simple-e-commerce-application-from-scratch-to-production-using-springboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 14:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/11/developing-a-simple-e-commerce-application-from-scratch-to-production-using-springboot/</guid>
      <description>We can find plenty of information on any technical topic, be it Java, .NET, Python or any frameworks like Spring, Hibernate, CDI, JSF etc. You can find hundreds of well written blogs on many of these topics. For example, you can find lot of tutorials on how to use SpringBoot or how to use various mappings in JPA/Hibernate or how to do form validations in JSF etc. Also, there are plenty of books published by well established publishers on most of the technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>