<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on SivaLabs</title>
    <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on SivaLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 05:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sivalabs.github.io/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Bloggers Meet at Hyderabad Oracle Campus Celebrating Java 20 Years Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/06/java-bloggers-meet-at-hyderabad-oracle-campus-celebrating-java-20-years-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 05:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2015/06/java-bloggers-meet-at-hyderabad-oracle-campus-celebrating-java-20-years-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Oracle arranged a nice Java Bloggers Meet at Hyderabad Oracle campus on 13th June 2015 and we celebrated Java 20th anniversary.
It is a pleasure to meet all the co-bloggers there and exchanged few thoughts on Java blogging. Also we are privileged to meet Java Champion Harshad Oak and Debraj Dutta who is the winner of Oracle IOT challenge.
Debraj Dutta demonstrated his Bot-So robot which is so cool. This robot actually took pictures of us and uploaded to GoogleDrive and shared on Twitter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Things That I Learned as a Blogger</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/10/few-things-that-i-learned-as-blogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 05:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2014/10/few-things-that-i-learned-as-blogger/</guid>
      <description>I started my career as a Java developer in 2006. I was working on a Servlets/JSP project based web application which we thought of migrating it to Struts framework.
I got some issue and struggling with it for hours and hours and couldn&amp;#8217;t be able to find any solution. I read all the Struts reference documentation and referred many books on Struts framework. But in all those books and reference documentation I could find the happy path situation guidelines only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome note</title>
      <link>https://sivalabs.github.io/2008/12/welcome-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 08:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sivalabs.github.io/2008/12/welcome-note/</guid>
      <description>Hi All,
Welcome guys. This is a blog where in you can find tutorials on various Java and J2EE technologies and can have discussions regarding technical problems and application development related issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>